"超感神探" 前情提要...
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
她说红约翰左肩上
She told me Red John has a tattoo
有个纹身... 三个点
on his left shoulder... three dots.
这就是我的筹码
That's my leverage.
把五个嫌疑人同时
Gather all five suspects together
聚在一个地方
at the same place, same time,
然后检查他们是否有纹身
and then start checking for the tattoo.
如何做到?
How do we do that?
- 周四晚上八点见  - 好吧
- Meet me at 8:00 on Thursday night.  - Fine.
周四晚上八点
Thursday night at 8:00.
- 我需要你帮个忙  - 好的 没问题
- I'll need your help.  - Well, then you've got it.
如果你不出现 他会觉得你就是红约翰
If you don't show up, he will assume you're Red John.
如果我去了 你和Jane就能
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
不再纠结"我是红约翰"这回事了?
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
一劳永逸
For once and for all.
你们真觉得能查到他了?
You really think you've got him?
- 是的  - 你们结案的时候我要在场
- I do.  - I want to be there when you end this.
我正等着你这么说呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
红约翰
Red John.
我非常愿意
Nothing would give me more pleasure
今晚去见你
than to be with you there tonight.
红约翰... 有纹身
Red John... has a tattoo.
在左臂上纹了三个点
Three dots on his left arm.
你们所有人...
And you all...
都要让我看一下...
are gonna show me...
现在
now.
开始吧
Let's go. Come on.
这就对了 脱下衣服
That's it. Take it off.
真是一派胡言
Nonsense.
很好
Very good.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
你找错人了
You got it wrong.
我不是红约翰
I'm not Red John.
Patrick 等一下 Patrick!
Patrick, wait. Patrick!
看... 这里
Look... Here.
看
Look.
站起来
On your feet.
到他俩那边
Over with those two.
哦... 天啊
Oh... God.
你们待在这里
You stay there.
你们三个...
Okay, you three...
对着墙... 站好
Over against that wall... now.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
等等! 不!
Wait! No!
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
协调：有个饭团    时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：捞盐    校对：影纸
啊!
Aah!
呼叫消防部队和紧急医疗小组
Call the fire department and EMTs.
告知他们这里有伤员数名
Let them know that there's multiple casualties,
还有拦好警戒线
and set up a perimeter.
把你的手电给我 我... 我进去看看
Give me your flashlight. I... I'm going in.
Smith探员
Agent Smith.
Smith探员 我是Teresa Lisbon
Agent Smith, it's Teresa Lisbon.
- 你还好吧?  - 发生什么了?
- Are you okay?  - What happened?
发生了一起爆炸 紧急医疗小组正火速赶来
There was an explosion. The EMTs are on their way.
他们会来救你的
They're gonna help you.
- 不许动!  - 怎么了?
- Don't move!  - What?
- 把手举起来 不然我就开枪了! 快把手举起来!  - 喔 喔 喔...
- Put your hands in the air, or I'll shoot! Do it!  - Whoa, whoa, whoa...
听着 我不知道你在说什么
Okay, listen, I don't know what you're talking about.
你一定是搞错了
You're clearly making a big mistake.
啊!
Aah!
Smith往哪边去了?
Which way did Smith go?
天啊 是你啊 Lisbon
Oh, my God, Lisbon.
咱们得找到Smith 他就是红约翰
We have to find Smith. He's Red John.
啊... 我去叫人来帮忙
Ah... I'll get help.
Jane啊?
Jane?
听得到吗?
Can you hear me?
Jane? 醒醒
Jane? Come on.
超感神探 第六季第7集
你还好吗?
You okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
医生说Jane的情况趋于稳定了
The doctors say Jane's stable.
没有什么重大损伤
There's no major trauma or anything.
只是还处于昏迷罢了
He's just not awake.
他们找到了三个人的遗体
They found the remains of three people.
基本确认分别是Bret Stiles 还有Ray Haffner
Positive I.D.s for Bret Stiles, Ray Haffner,
和Thomas Mcallister
and Thomas Mcallister.
你确定吗? 我还以为
Are you sure? I would think
连核武器都弄不死Bret Stiles呢
Bret Stiles would survive a nuclear attack.
尸体都烧焦了
The bodies are all burnt to a crisp,
但技术组还是找到了对应的DNA进行测试
but the crime techs did spot DNA tests.
验尸间将其比对以往就医记录
Coroner's office checked it against medical records.
Stiles Haffner 还有Mcallister都确认死亡
Stiles, Haffner, and Mcallister are all positively dead.
呃 那Smith呢? 有没有人目击?
Uh, what about Smith? Any sightings?
暂时没有 Rigsby和Van Pelt在查
Not yet. Rigsby and Van Pelt are on it.
嗯
Hmm.
头儿?
Sir?
- 啊 就觉得在这儿能找到你  - 您没事吧?
- Ah, thought I might find you here.  - Are you all right?
呃 我没事 不过我倒是想喝杯咖啡
Uh, I'm fine. I could use a cup of coffee, actually.
你能去帮我泡一杯吗?
Would you go and get me one?
我们正要组织对Smith的搜寻工作
We're just about to coordinate the manhunt for Smith.
那你就去把他抓来啊
Well, you should just go and get him.
我想留在这儿 头儿
Well, I'd like to stay here, sir.
Cho他们... 能搞定的
Well, are... Cho and the team... They can handle it.
你这是在公然违抗命令?
Are you refusing a direct order?
当然不是
Well, no.
- 不 我只是想留在这陪他  - 你... 你就不能听我的话吗?
- No, I just want to stay here with him.  - Wh... why don't you listen a little more closely?
我在命令你即刻离开这
I am ordering you to get out there,
把你的小组组织好 去抓Smith
put your team together, and get Smith.
Jane? Jane? 该死 那个呼叫按钮去哪了?
Jane? Jane? Where's the damn call button?
我... 我去把护士叫来
I'll... I'll get the nurse.
Jane啊
Jane.
嘿
Hey.
我们推测红约翰带了炸弹来
Our working theory is that Red John brought in the bomb
想置Jane和其他嫌疑人于死地
to kill Jane and the other suspects.
好吧 可是怎么做到的呢?
Okay, but how?
可能是红约翰将炸弹藏在了自己身上
Chances are, Red John snuck the bomb in on his person.
技术组从墙里挖出了
Crime techs have pulled fragments of the bomb casings
弹壳的碎片... 非常小的碎片
from the walls... very small fragments.
这说明他带的炸药是高密集 高火力的
This tells us that the explosive was dense, high-powered.
听起来不像是自制的
That doesn't sound homemade.
不 我认为是军用级别的
No. Military grade's my bet,
也就是说有迹可循
which means it could be traceable.
最有可能是这些地方来的
These are the most likely sources.
查一查其中有没有
Check for any recent thefts
- 最近失窃或遗失的炸药  - 没问题 这就去查
- of missing explosives from any of them.  - All right, will do.
- 有线索了?  - 嗯
- Got something?  - Yeah.
Lisbon在Smith逃走前给了他一枪
Lisbon wounded Smith before he escaped.
他现在身上中了一弹
He's walking around with a bullet.
医院接受枪伤病人时都要报告警局的
Oh. Well, hospitals have to declare gunshot wounds,
所以他不能去正规的急诊室
so he can't go to an ER.
所以他需要找个能保持缄默的医生
Right, so he needs a doctor who'll keep quiet.
萨克拉门托这里是Smith的地盘
Smith's based here in Sacramento,
我查了查他以前在这附近办的案子
so I looked into some of his old cases around town.
去年在南萨克拉门托 一支武装小组逮捕了
He was part of a task force that arrested
一个叫Alek Lavrov的医生 而他便是小组一员
Dr. Alek Lavrov last year in South Sac.
还有一名违法开奥施康定的Feelgood医生
A Dr. Feelgood writing illegal oxycontin scripts.
- 然后?  - 然后案子不了了之
- So?  - So the case went bad,
证据也没了 Lavrov无罪开释
evidence was lost, and Lavrov walked.
所以Smith一定知道去哪儿找
So Smith knows exactly where to find a doctor
不会跟警察告密的医生 很好 咱们去看看
who won't talk to the cops. Okay, let's go check it out.
你找错人了
It's not what you think.
我不是红约翰
I'm not Red John.
Patrick 等一下 看
Patrick, wait. Look.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
Lisbon啊
Lisbon.
你房子里发生了一起爆炸
There was an explosion at your house.
我昏迷多长时间了?
How long have I been out?
十二小时了
12 hours.
Reede Smith是红约翰
Reede Smith is Red John.
我看到他肩膀上的纹身了
I saw the tattoo on his shoulder.
不光他一个
He's not the only one.
Mcallister也有一个
Mcallister has one, too.
他死了 Stiles和Haffner也死了
He's dead. So are Stiles and Haffner.
- 还有Bertram  - Bertram?
- And Bertram.  - Bertram?
他也有纹身
He has the tattoo as well.
天啊
Oh, my god.
他刚刚还在这
He was just here.
站在你身旁
He was standing over you.
他... 他还想把我支开
He... he was trying to get me to leave.
他刚才想杀你
He was gonna kill you.
- 我的衣服呢?  - 别急 好吗?
- Where are my clothes?  - Slow down, okay?
- 别...  - 不 我没事 时间紧迫
- Just...  - No, it's okay. We don't have time.
Jane 等等
Jane. Jane.
我的衣服呢?
Where are my clothes?
我是Teresa Lisbon
This is Teresa Lisbon.
向全州发布对Reede Smith和Gail Bertram的
Put out a statewide alert for the apprehension
逮捕令
of Reede Smith and Gail Bertram.
没错 就是Bertram局长
Yes, Director Bertram.
小心靠近
Approach with caution.
他们是手持武器的亡命之徒
They're considered armed and dangerous.
他们两人中的一个就是红约翰
One of them is Red John.
啊!
Aah!
走开 女士 警察局的事
Move along, ma'am. Police business.
啊! 天啊!
Aah! God!
很好
Yes.
子弹还在你的体内
The bullet is still inside you.
别废话! 快取出来!
No crap! Get it out!
会很疼的
This is going to hurt.
你确定不要吃点止疼药?
Are you sure you won't take something for the pain?
不要...
No...
不要 我得保持清醒
No. I gotta stay sharp.
随你便吧
As you like.
啊!
Aah!
天啊!
God!
老虎 老虎
Tiger, tiger.
Smith在里面?
Smith in there?
是的 叫得跟杀猪似的
Yeah. He's screaming his head off.
干掉他不是问题 你怎么打算的?
He won't be a problem. How you wanna do it?
我刚从加州调查局得到内部消息
I just got word from inside CBI.
这会儿有几个探员正赶来这找Smith
Couple of agents are coming here right now looking for Smith.
- 我们怎么办?  - 加快动作
- So what do we do?  - We hurry.
你去找他 要是加州调查局来人我负责周旋
You go get him. I'll run interference if CBI shows.
没问题
You got it.
嘿
Hey.
把他带到后面去 在那儿干掉他
Take him out the back. Do it there.
啊! 啊!
Aah! Aah!
- 是他逼我的 我是无辜的  - 闭嘴
- He made me do this. I'm innocent.  - Shut up.
原本他一走我就打算打电话报警的
I would have called the police as soon as he left.
- 我不想惹麻烦!  - 别吵!
- I don't want any trouble!  - Quiet!
你是组织的?
You association?
老虎 老虎 你干嘛不向我们求助?
Tiger, tiger. Why didn't you call us?
真滑稽 是你们不信任我的
Funnily enough, I got trust issues.
嘿 都是朋友怎么会不信任
Hey, you gotta trust your friends.
我是来帮你的 能下地走路吗?
I'm here to help you. Can you walk?
我得帮他缝好 他会流血的
I need to sew him up. He'll bleed.
啊... 我能走路
Ah... I can walk.
啊!
Aah!
Cordero探长 是吧?
Detective Cordero, right?
Rigsby探员
Agent Rigsby.
最近怎么样?
How are ya?
他是萨克拉门托警察局的 办过Kirkland的那个枪击案
He's, uh, Sac P.D. Worked the Kirkland shooting.
- 这位是Grace Van Pelt探员  - 嗨
- This is Agent Grace Van Pelt.  - Hi.
什么风把你们吹到南萨克拉门托来啦?
What brings you to South Sac?
- 我们在搜捕Reede...  - Reede Smith? 又称红约翰
- We're chasing up a lead on Reede...  - Reede Smith? AKA Red John.
看来我们比你们早来一步
Looks like we beat you to the punch.
我的一个部下已经进去抓他了
One of my guys is in there getting him right now.
需要我们掩护吗?
You want us to cover the back?
- 不 不 我们没问题的  - 你确定?
- No. No, we got it.  - You sure?
嘿 尽管我们不是加州调查局的 可分内的事总不会出差错的
Hey, we might not be CBI, but we know what we're doing.
好吧 失陪一下
Okay. Excuse me.
什么事?
Yep?
Rigsby 你在哪呢?
Rigsby, where are you?
在医生门外 看来Smith就在里面
Outside the doctor's office. Looks like Smith's inside.
你身边有警察吗?
Are there policemen with you?
有啊 怎么了?
Yeah. Why?
好 听仔细
Okay, listen carefully.
不要相信执法体系内的任何人
Do not trust anyone in law enforcement.
任何人也不要相信 明白吗?
Anyone at all. Do you understand?
明白了 多谢
You got it. Thanks.
咱们到后面去看看
Let's, uh, go take a look around back.
等一下
Wait a minute.
嘿! 你们去哪儿?
Hey! Where're you going?
车在这后边
Car's back this way.
事情都安排好了
Everything's taken care of.
附近有个安全屋 可以提供新衣服 医生...
We got a safe house nearby, fresh clothes, a doctor...
就在城外
A trip out of town.
安全屋?
A safe house, huh?
这话我也跟别人说过
You know, I said that to someone once.
是吗? 后来呢?
Yeah? What happened after that?
我对着他的后背开了六枪
I shot him six times in the back.
来吧
Come on.
啊...
Ah...
该死
Damn it.
放下武器!
Drop your weapon!
站住!
Stop!
- 你还好吧?  - 嗯! 你没事吧?
- You all right?  - Yeah! You good?
没事
Yeah.
打斗中Smith溜了
Smith got away during the fight.
那个探长也溜了
So did the detective.
头儿 他们要杀Smith和我们 为什么?
Boss, they were trying to kill Smith and us. Why?
- 不知道  - 查看一下肩膀
- I don't know.  - Check the shoulder.
- 什么?  - 叫他查看一下左肩
- What?  - Ask him to check the left shoulder.
让Rigsby把那人的衬衫脱下来查看一下左肩
Have Rigsby take his shirt off and look at his shoulder.
Lisbon想让你查看一下他的左肩
Lisbon wants you to check his left shoulder.
怎么回事?
What the hell?
没错 他有纹身的
He's got it. He's got the tattoo.
头儿 怎么回事?
Boss, what's happening?
好 把他带来
All right, bring him in
别让任何人靠近
and don't let anybody else get to him.
带他走
Bring him in.
那个朝你们开枪的警察 我们了解多少?
What do we know about the cop who attacked you?
这个是我们抓到的 Paul Wiehagen警员
This is the one we caught. Officer Paul Wiehagen.
任职六年 记录优良
Six years on the force. Exemplary record,
获得过几次褒奖 没有重大原则性错误
a couple of commendations, no real discipline problems.
- 那另外一个... Cordero探长呢?  - 我们给他的队长打了电话
- What about the other one... Detective Cordero?  - Put a call in to his captain.
说他一小时前请了病假
Said he called in sick an hour ago.
而且还是没有发现Bertram的踪迹
And still no sign of Bertram.
咱们把精力集中在已有的线索上
Let's focus on the one we do have.
或许Jane能问出什么来
Maybe Jane will figure it out.
有人派你去杀Reede Smith吗?
Did someone send you to kill Reede Smith?
无可奉告
I got nothing to say.
你为什么要杀他?
Why were you gonna murder him?
那个纹身呢? 是什么含义?
What about the tattoo? What's it mean?
我懂了 你不大善于言辞
You're not a big talker. I get it.
"嘴管不牢 办事不牢" 没错吧
Loose lips sink ships and all that.
不幸的是 你的表情还不够淡定
The bad news is, you have a lousy poker face.
所以咱们玩个"我说你做"的小游戏
So we're gonna play a little game of show-and-tell.
我会告诉你一些事情 你通过面部表情
I'm gonna tell you something, and you're gonna show me
告诉我说对了没有
with your face whether I'm right or not.
听起来挺有趣吧?
That sound fun?
你偷过东西吗?
You ever steal anything?
背叛过你的女朋友吗?
Did you ever cheat on your girlfriend?
打过她?
Hit her?
你喜欢给别人带来痛苦?
Do you like causing pain?
我这辈子从没打过任何一个女人
I never hit a woman in my life.
你是否属于一个由警察
Do you belong to a secret organization of cops
和其他政府官员组成的秘密组织?
and other government officials?
看来是的
Yes.
你曾为这个组织
You've committed crimes
犯过罪
on behalf of that organization before.
对吧?
Right?
Smith探员也是成员之一...
Agent Smith is a member also...
对吧?
right?
组织派你到医生那里
The organization sent you to the doctor's office
杀了他... 对吧?
to kill him... right?
加州调查局局长Gail Bertram也是成员之一
CBI Director Gail Bertram is also a member.
你不知道
You don't know.
级别太低 权限不够是吧?
Too low on the totem pole, huh?
Reede Smith探员是红约翰
Agent Reede Smith is Red John.
也不知道
Don't know.
Gail Bertram是红约翰
Gail Bertram's Red John.
还是不知道
Don't know.
你肩膀上的那个纹身是入会标志
That tattoo on your shoulder is the membership sign.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我又说对了
Right again.
还有个口令...
There's a password, too...
你们在碰头或者...
something you say as a greeting or a...
求救时说的
distress signal.
"老虎 老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
从我脑袋里滚出去
Get out of my head.
一个坏警察构成的秘密组织
A secret society of dirty cops.
而红约翰是成员之一
And Red John's a member.
还有Partridge
Partridge.
他在死前跟我说了"老虎 老虎"
He said "Tiger, tiger" to me right before he died.
嗯 没错 没错
Hmm. Yes. Yes.
他在向你求救
He was asking for help
希望你万一也是成员之一
in the hopes that you were a member.
但他要是有纹身的话
But if he had a tattoo,
尸检报告里应该会写啊
it would have been in the autopsy report.
档案是可以造假的
Well, you can't trust a file.
眼见为实
We have to see it.
我派Cho去查尸体的下落
I'll have Cho track down the body.
但Partridge现在可能已经埋了
But Partridge could be buried by now.
那就让Cho带上铲子
Well, have Cho bring a shovel.
已经派人在找Smith 而Bertram跑了
The team's looking for Smith, Bertram's on the run.
到底谁是红约翰?
So who's Red John?
是Bertram还是Smith?
Is it Bertram or Smith?
我得直视他们的眼睛才行
I need to look them both in the eye.
验尸官大概两天前把尸体送了过来
Yeah, the coroner released his body, like, two days ago.
- 是谋杀案受害者吧?  - 没错
- Murder victim, huh?  - Yeah.
我猜也是 所以验尸官才拖了这么久
I figured. That's why we held him for so long.
还好你今天来了
Good thing you got here today.
明天他就烧得剩不下多少了
Tomorrow there won't be much left of him to look at.
来吧
Here we go.
Brett Partridge是吧
Brett Partridge.
帮我一把 好吗?
Give me a hand, huh?
随便看吧
He's all yours.
把刀给我
Give me your knife.
火化之前要给他们穿戴整齐
They dress 'em before we burn 'em.
我可不知道为什么
Don't ask me why.
Cho发来张图片
Cho sent a picture.
这是什么意思?
What does it mean?
你觉得呢?
What do you think it means?
Smith那边怎么回事?
What happened with Smith?
在医生那里差点让他们抓住了
They almost got him at his doctor's office.
那个加州调查局的小组突然出现
That CBI team showed up.
Smith逃之夭夭了
Smith's in the wind.
逃得真快
That's a good place to be.
我在这有点事要办
I've got some business in here,
在这儿等我
so wait for me.
啊 谢谢 Tomas先生
Ah. Thank you,Mr. Thomas.
有日子没见着您了
We haven't seen you for a while.
是啊 很高兴见到你
Yeah. It's nice to see you.
Smith现在可能在任何地方
Smith could be anywhere by now.
我试着追踪过他手机的GPS信号
I tried to trace the GPS Signal on his cell phone.
好几个小时没动静了
It's been dead for hours.
他那样的联邦调查局问题探员手头肯定会有预付费的备用机
A dirty FBI agent like him has to have a burner.
Lavrov医生说他没来得及给Smith缝好线
Dr. Lavrov says he didn't get the chance to sew Smith up.
他现在身上仍然有枪伤
He's still walking around with a bullet wound.
所以无论他在哪 情况都不妙
So he's in a bad way wherever he is.
总会有人发现他的
He'll get picked up by someone eventually.
是啊 但要是哪个警察找到他...
Yeah, but any cop who finds him...
太可怕了 我们谁也不能相信了
This is scary. We can't trust anyone.
没错
Nope.
啊 啊
Aah. Aah.
我是Van Pelt探员
Agent Van Pelt.
你得帮我
You gotta help me.
是Smith探员
Agent Smith.
他们要杀我
They're gonna kill me.
我要投降
I wanna surrender.
你在哪?
Where are you?
在市中心 叫Cho过去 他应该在附近
Downtown. Call Cho. He should be close.
好的 我们这就到
Okay, we're on our way.
Smith向加州调查局求助了
Smith reached out to CBI.
他用了组织给他的备用机
He used the burner the association gave him.
我们都听到了
We were listening.
他要自首
He's turning himself in.
是啊 叛徒
Yeah. Rat.
那个加州调查局小组正赶往那边接他
That CBI team is on its way to get him now.
不能让他落到那帮人手里 他在哪?
Well, we can't have that. Where is he?
就在离这不远的巷子里 算咱们运气好
He's in an alley not too far from here. Our good luck.
他知道你是谁吗?
Does he know who you are?
不知道 在医生那里他没见到我
Nah, he didn't see me at the doctor's office.
很好 那你现在就装成一名加州调查局探员
All right. You are now a CBI Agent.
想一起来吗? 应该会很有意思
You want to come along? Could be fun.
不了 我还有其它事要办
No. I have some other business to take care of.
- 一会儿见  - 没问题
- We'll meet up later.  - You got it.
这次能别再把事情搞砸吗?
Can you get it right this time?
明白!
Yes, Sir!
啊!
Aah!
嗯...
Mm...
Reede Smith探员?
Agent Reede Smith?
你在吗? Van Pelt探员派我过来的
You out there? Agent Van Pelt sent me.
你是谁?
Who are you?
Oscar Cordero探员 加州调查局的
Agent Oscar Cordero, CBI.
我来接你回去
I'm here to take you in.
你得保证我的安全
You gotta keep me safe.
他们简直无孔不入
They're everywhere.
没错
Yeah.
我们的确是无孔不入
We are.
老天...
God...
快到车后座去
Back of the car now.
你不会真觉得能躲过我们吧?
You didn't really think you could get away from us, did you?
你是个大孩子了 帮我个忙
You're a big boy. Do me a favor
自己钻后备箱里去
and get in the trunk yourself.
让我歇口气 好吗?
Just give me a second, will you?
你先进后备箱再说
You'll have a second in the trunk.
别逼我对你动手
Now don't make me do painful things to you.
进车里去!
Get in the car!
咱们得事先说好 完全豁免
I'm gonna need a deal. Full immunity.
除非能放我走 不然我一个字也不会说的
I'm not saying a word unless I can walk.
那你走吧
So walk.
什么?
What?
把你的肥屁股抬起来走吧
Get up off your ass and walk.
不过别忘了 没等你出这栋楼
But, hey, good luck getting out of the building
就会有老朋友去和你"叙叙旧"了
before your friends catch up with you.
只要你把知道的都告诉我们
If you tell us everything we need to know,
我保证把你送到远离加利福尼亚的
I promise we will put you in a Federal prison
联邦监狱
far away from California.
那样你才会安全
Someplace that you'll be safe.
五年前 我弄伤了背
Five years ago, I hurt my back.
当时在帮我表弟搬沙发
I was helping my cousin move a stupid couch.
医生给我开了些止痛片
Doctor gave me some pain pills.
结果我对其产生了依赖
Turns out I liked them.
我还一头雾水的时候 就根本停不下来了
I got hooked before I even knew what was happening.
然后?
So?
然后...
So...
我在Carson Springs的巷子里
I'm chasing a gangbanger down an alley
追捕一个轮奸犯的时候 情绪失控了
in Carson Springs, and I'm out of it.
真的完全失控了
I mean, way out of it.
我当时... 我当时以为有人跟踪我
I thought... I thought I was being followed.
我开枪打死了一个小女孩
I shot a little girl.
一个12岁的小女孩
A 12-year-old girl.
当地警察采了我的血样
Local cops took my blood.
他们有目击证人 证据确凿
They had witnesses. They had me cold.
然后这个探长突然出现
And then this detective,
他过来跟我说
he reaches out to me and he says
他们能让这一切都烟消云散
they can make it all go away.
他们也确实做到了
And they did.
血样测试 目击证人... 都搞定了?
The blood tests, the witnesses... all of it?
岂止 他们搞定之后
Hell, when they got done fixing it,
联邦调查局还给我颁了一块勋章
the FBI gave me a medal.
所谓"他们"到底是谁?
And exactly who are "they"?
我们自称"布雷克组织"
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
为什么?
Why?
"老虎 老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
"老虎 老虎 双眼绿光闪"
"Tyger, tyger burning bright."
出自布雷克的诗作
From the poem by Blake.
看来有人很喜欢这首诗啊
Someone's a big fan of his, I guess.
还有谁在这个组织里?
Well, who else is in the association?
警察 法官 联邦调查局探员
Cops, judges, FBI Agents.
任何在执法体系中有事要瞒的人
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
比如你的毒瘾
Like your drug habit.
需要帮忙 只管张口
You need a favor, you ask for it.
找你帮忙 只管办事
You get asked to do something, you do it.
"老虎 老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
没错
Yep.
有没有什么负责人之类的?
Well, is there somebody who's in charge?
肯定有吧
Must be.
但我不知道是谁
But I don't know who.
我就了解我周围一小圈人
I just know my little group. That's it.
但我猜
But I'm guessing
像我们这样的一定有上百吧 甚至上千
there must be hundreds of us, maybe thousands.
而且藏得滴水不漏?
And nobody knows about it?
Bob Kirkland知情了 对吧?
Bob Kirkland knew about it, didn't he?
说吧 别压在心头了
Go ahead, just say it. Unburden yourself.
没错
Yeah.
他知道的太多了
He knew too much.
所以我杀了他
So I killed him.
你知不知道 红约翰是否是
Do you know that Red John's a member
布雷克组织的一员?
of the Blake Association?
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
红约翰曾经有个追随者
Red John had a follower.
叫Rebecca Anderson
Rebecca Anderson.
大概四年前杀了一些你们的人
Killed some of your guys about four years ago.
没错 Sam Bosco和他的团队
Yeah, Sam Bosco and his team.
是他们
Them.
有人要我搞到联邦调查局的身份证明
Someone asked me to get FBI credentials
从而他们能够进入加州调查局
so that they could access CBI.
红约翰自己或者哪个为他办事的人
Red John or someone who worked for him
偷偷溜进加州调查局给Rebecca下了毒
snuck into the CBI and poisoned Rebecca.
而你暗中顺水推舟?
And you helped them?
我是后来才知道的
I mean, that's when I knew.
我... 我帮了连环杀手一个忙
I'd... I'd done a favor for a serial killer.
谁让你搞那个身份证明的?
Who asked you to get the credentials?
不知道 电话里说的
I don't know. It was a phone call.
组织就是这样运作的
That's the way the association works.
永远是黑箱
You never know.
你们...
You...
你们能保护我的安全的吧?
you're gonna be able to keep me safe, right?
要看情况
That depends.
是不是你杀了我的老婆和女儿?
Did you murder my wife and daughter?
我没杀你的老婆和女儿
I did not murder your wife and daughter.
我以我母亲的名誉发誓
I swear on my mother.
你相信他吗?
Do you believe him?
他对谋杀供认不讳
He confessed to murder.
红约翰是不会这样崩溃的 即使是假戏也不会真做到这个地步
Red John would never break like that, not even as an act.
- 既然Smith不是红约翰...  - 那就意味着我们有事情做了
- Well, if Smith isn't Red John...  - That means we have work to do.
我们需要帮助 谁接任了Brenda Shettrick?
And we need help. Who took over from Brenda Shettrick?
媒体部的? 怎么了?
In media relations? Why?
感谢大家在如此匆忙的通知下依旧前来
Thank you for coming on such short notice.
我们请来了加州调查局的顾问Patrick Jane
We have CBI consultant Patrick Jane here,
他前来向大家报告在红约翰一案中的
Who is here to report a development
最新进展
in the Red John case.
谢谢
Thank you.
十年前
Ten years ago,
人称红约翰的连环杀手
the serial killer known as Red John
杀害了我的老婆和女儿
killed my wife and daughter.
呃 自那以后我们一刻也不曾停歇对其的搜捕
Uh, we've been hunting him diligently ever since.
时至今日 我们很欣慰地宣布
Today we're pleased to announce
我们... 我们终于确认了他的名字 他的长相
that we... we finally have a name, a face.
加州调查局的局长
The Director of the division of law enforcement,
Gail Bertram就是红约翰
Gail Bertram, is Red John.
他是手持武器的亡命之徒
He's armed and dangerous.
如果有人看到他 不要靠近
If you see him, do not approach him.
请立刻告知加州调查局
Call the California Bureau of Investigation at once.
谢谢
Thank you.
一个一个提问
One question at a time.
失礼了 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
咱们要不要探讨一下?
So are we gonna talk about this?
探讨什么?
Talk about what?
Bertram是红约翰这事
Bertram is Red John.
看来是的
Looks like.
要是Jane找到他 就会杀了他
And if Jane finds him, he's gonna kill him.
没错
Yeah.
我们不会感觉奇怪吗? 把头儿杀了?
And we're good with that? Killing the boss?
我不会
I am.
我也不会
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
幸好我们的观点一致
Just as long as we're on the same page.
就感觉怪怪的
It's just weird, is all.
Bertram吸烟吗?
Does Bertram smoke?
不吧
No, I don't think so.
有时候可能是礼物
People get them as gifts sometimes.
- Van Pelt  - 嗯?
- Van Pelt.  - Hmm?
嗯 原来是个闪存
Hmm. A flash drive.
咱们来看看
Let's take a look.
只有一个文件
There's only one file on the drive.
有密码保护的
It's password-protected.
我得强行打开
I'll have to brute-force it.
正好 我一直想试试我全新的现场可编程门阵列
Cool. I've been wanting to use my new FPGA.
你的什么?
Your what?
相信我 千万别问
Trust me, don't ask.
然后就...
And...
打开了
we're in.
该死
Crap.
看起来像个清单
It looks like a list.
可能是份名单? 你能解码吗?
Names, maybe? Can you decode it?
我能小试一下...
I can try a few things...
但解码是Jane的专长吧
but decoding is Jane's department.
我给他发过去
I'll send it to him.
给你 这杯可是这儿的招牌
Here you go. This one isn't messing around.
不加冰
Lots of peat.
嗯 不错 能放些冰块进去吗?
Yeah, that's pretty good. Can you put some rocks in it?
真要放吗? 这杯苏格兰威士忌很正的
Are you sure? This is some fine scotch.
让你放你就放
Yeah, I'm sure.
那人跟你长得真像
That guy looks like you.
载我一程
I need a ride.
我们正赶往酒吧
We're en route to the bar now.
高速巡警把公路封闭了
Highway patrol shut down the freeways,
如果他要跑 我们就能抓到他了 但要是他藏起来呢?
so if he runs, we've got him, but what if he hides?
Bertram在Citrus Heights杀了酒保
Bertram killed the bartender in Citrus Heights.
他有个婶婶住在那
He's got an aunt with a house there.
你觉得他藏在那儿了?
You think that's where he is?
她大概半年前搬进了退休房
She moved into a retirement home about six months ago,
所以她那边现在没人住
so her place is empty now.
听起来像是个好的藏身之处 地址呢?
Sounds like a good place to hide. What's the address?
Rosemary街1408号
1408 Rosemary Street.
我们正在赶来 派Cho和RRT立刻到那里去
We're on our way. Get Cho and RRT there now,
并且通知直升机
and let the choppers know.
- 他在里面吗?  - 反正要是在的话 肯定跑不了了
- Is he here?  - If he is, he's in there.
我让Karl和其他几个人守在后面
I got Karl and a few guys in the back.
- 他哪儿也别想去  - 那些人值得信任吗?
- He's not going anywhere.  - Do we trust them?
我查看了他们的肩膀和纹身
I asked to see their shoulders and their tattoos.
你们来干嘛? 我没叫萨克拉门托警察局的特警队过来
What are you doing here? I didn't call Sac P.D. S.W.A.T.
有人叫了
Well, someone asked for us.
就在这组建一个指挥中心!
Let's set up a command center right here!
各位听好 总负责是我!
Listen, everybody, I'm in charge!
谁授的权? 明明是我们先来的 他们是从北区来的
Who authorized that? We're primary on the scene. They came from northern district.
离这边远着呢 到底怎么回事?
That's way across town. What the hell is going on?
是他 他叫他们过来的
He did it. He called them in.
Bertram叫特警来他自己这儿干什么?
Well, why would Bertram call S.W.A.T. to his own location?
他不光叫了一支特警队
He didn't call in one S.W.A.T. team.
他把他们全都叫来了
He called all of them in.
简直乱套了
This is a madhouse.
后面又有个行动组莫名其妙开始组建了
There's a whole 'nother unit setting up out back.
场面要失控了 头儿
We've lost control of the scene, boss.
他就藏在里面 Bertram是其中之一
He's one of them. Bertram is one of them.
他要脱身了 咱们得控制场面
He's getting away. We gotta shut it down.
谁也不准离开!
Nobody leaves!
No one leaves!
你安全了
You're clear.
是啊...
Yeah...
我得吃点东西
I need something to eat.
中国菜如何? 我知道一家不错的地方
How about Chinese? I know a great place.
好啊 听起来不错
Yeah, sounds good.
他们在屋里找到了Bertram的衣物
They found Bertram's clothes inside the house.
看来有人在他来之前就预先放了一套特警队服
Looks like someone planted a S.W.A.T. team outfit
在他房子里
in the house before he got there.
然后他们把附近所有的特警队和RRT叫了过去
And then called every S.W.A.T. and RRT in the area.
有没有线索是谁联系的?
Any leads about who made all those calls?
一个能够操纵多方关系的人
Somebody who could pull a lot of strings at once.
布雷克组织
Blake Association.
头儿
Boss.
请注意 好吗?
May I have your attention, please?
放下你们手里的电话 离开你们的桌椅
Put down your phones and step away from your desks.
快
Now.
我是这儿的负责人 Teresa Lisbon特别探员
I'm Special Agent in charge Teresa Lisbon.
你是谁?
Who the hell are you?
联邦调查局监管探员Dennis Abbott
FBI Supervisory Agent Dennis Abbott.
我重复一遍 起身
Now I repeat, stand up
离开你们的座椅...
and stand away from your desks...
请吧
please.
我们正忙着追捕一个
We're in the middle of a manhunt
亡命之徒
for a dangerous fugitive.
如果您想帮忙的话...
Now if you would like to assist...
这个执法机构的头儿
The head of this alleged law enforcement organization
居然是个杀人犯
is a murderer,
还是一个大型犯罪组织的成员
and a member of a massive criminal conspiracy.
联邦调查局探员同样混迹其中
Which included FBI Agents.
没错 这也是为什么局里从德克萨斯分局的奥斯丁
Yes, and that's why the Bureau sent me here
派我过来
from the Austin, Texas Office.
来清理门户
To clean up the mess.
我手里的是
I am holding in my hand
联邦法官起草的书面命令
a writ from a federal judge.
联邦调查局将关闭你们的部门
The FBI's closing down your organization right now.
所有人
All of you
从现在开始
are relieved from your active duties
解职
as of this moment.
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
我是来收集证据的
I'm here to collect evidence.
别不识相
Don't get in my way.
大家开干吧
Let's go to work, fellas.
哇 哇 哇 什么情况?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. What's going on here?
这是你的
That's yours.
Dennis Abbott 联邦调查局的 你想必是Patrick Jane了
Dennis Abbott, FBI. You must be Patrick Jane.
他们把我们的部门关了
They've shut us down.
到时候会找你谈谈的
We're gonna need to interview you at some point,
不过不急 反正我们会在这里待上一阵子
but it can wait. We're gonna be here for some time.
别离开就行
Just don't leave town.
我们还要抓杀人犯呢
We have a killer to catch.
这个嘛 由我们来担心好了
Oh, well, that's our problem now.
给过你机会 可是你没有把握住...
You had your chance to catch him and you blew it...
当然你可能根本没努力
if you were really trying.
这是我最喜欢的杯子
That was my favorite cup.
行
Yeah.
好吧 后会有期
Okay, well, you see in the funny pages.
现在怎么办?
What now?
不知道
I don't know.
Van Pelt在Bertram办公室里找到了一些加密文档
Van Pelt found some coded files in Bertram's office.
我们应该着手去查吗?
Should we get started on those?
不 都是浪费时间 我们没戏了
No, it's a waste of time. We're done.
没什么好做的了
There's nothing more to do here.
回家吧 休息休息
Just go home, get some rest.
我不相信 你不可能就这么放弃的
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
不 我没放弃
No, I'm not quitting.
呃...
Uh...
我只是放手了
I'm letting go.
事情已经不归我们管了
It's out of our hands for now.
我会和你联系的 好吗?
But I'll be in touch. Okay?
抱歉了 为过去的一切
I'm sorry. For everything.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：有个饭团    时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：捞盐    校对：影纸